Register of the United States National Student Association International Commission records
Hoover Institution Archives
United States National Student Association International Commission records
1946-1968
68011
Hoover Institution Archives
324 manuscript boxes, 7 envelopes (135.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, minutes of meetings, bulletins, circulars, questionnaires, notes, lists, financial records, printed matter, photographs, and sound recordings relating to the international activities of the association, including delegation and scholarship exchanges with other nations, American representation at annual International Student Conferences, relations with analogous student organizations abroad, and the effects of world politics on education.
United States National Student Association. International Commission.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1968.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
Founded in 1947 in Madison, Wisconsin, the United States National Student Association is a confederation of student bodies at American colleges and universities represented through their democratically-elected student government. The Association gives expression to student opinion, seeks to increase students' responsibility and contribution to the college community, and works to strengthen relations between American students and those in other countries. Specific activities include operating a national clearing house for information on student activities, cooperating with major educational and civil rights organizations, sponsoring national student literary magazine contests and student government achievement awards, conducting regional and national conferences, and making studies of various student-related problems.
The International Commission is a division of the U.S. National Student Association and administers the international activities of the Association. It conducts delegation and scholarship exchanges with other nations, sends an American representative to the International Student Conference, and maintains relations with analogous student organizations in other countries, called national unions of students. The U.S. National Student Association meets annually at various places with the other national unions at an International Student Conference. A permanent, non-policy making body, called the Coordinating Secretariat, administers the programs decided upon at the international conference. Another organization, with which the International Commission interacts but of which it is not a member, is the International Union of Students, a tightly structured network of student groups in communist-controlled countries.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, minutes of meetings, bulletins, circulars, questionnaires, notes, lists, financial records, printed matter, photographs, and sound recordings relating to the international activities of the association, including delegation and scholarship exchanges with other nations, American representation at annual International Student Conferences, relations with analogous student organizations abroad, and the effects of world politics on education.
Audiotapes.; Education--United States.; International education.; Student movements--United States.; Student movements.; United States--Relations.; Universities and colleges--United States.
- COORDINATING SECRETARIAT FILE, 1951-1965
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, reports, memoranda, minutes of meetings, bulletins, circulars, questionnaires, and financial records collected by the NSA International Commission and relating to the programs that were mandated by the National Unions of Students at the International Student Conferences and administered by its Coordinating Secretariat, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Conferences and seminars (Box 1)
    - African Delegation, 1954
    - African Seminar, 1960 January ll - February 8
    - Afro-Asian Student Conference, 1955-1956 (Box 314)
    - Agricultural Seminar, 1955-1957 (Box 1)
    - Asian Delegation, 1955
    - Asian Regional Cooperation Seminar, 2nd, 1961
    - Asian Student Press Conference, 1956-1957
    - Asian Student Study Seminar Report, 1958
    - Asian Team, 1955-1956
    - Asian Team, 1955-1956 (Box 314)
    - Conference on Cultural Activities, 1954-1957 (Box 1)
    - International Bureau for Cultural Activities, 1957-1962
    - International Student Conference, 1950-1951
    - International Student Conference, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - International Student Conference, 1953-1954 (Box 3)
    - International Student Conference, 1955-1956 (Box 4)
    - International Student Conference, 1956-1958 (Box 5)
    - International Student Conference, 1958-1959 (Box 6)
    - International Student Conference, 1959-1960 (Box 7)
    - International Student Conference, 1960-1962 (Box 8)
    - International Student Conference, 1962-1964 (Box 9)
    - International Student Conference, 1964-1966 (Box 10)
    - International Student Conference, 1968 (Box 315)
    - International Conference on Student Housing, 1949-1950 (Box 10)
    - International Roundtable Conference, 1959-1960
    - International Student Cultural Festival (Box 11)
    - International Student Press Conference, 4th, 1954
    - International Student Press Conference, 5th, 1955
    - International Student Press Conference, 6th, 1956
    - International Student Press Conference, 7th, 1957
    - International Student Press Conference, 11th, 1963
    - International Student Seminar, 2nd, 1951
    - International Student Seminar, 6th, 1955
    - International Student Seminar, 7th, 1956
    - International Student Seminar, 8th, 1957
    - International Student Seminar, 13th, 1962
    - International Student Seminar, 14th, 1963 (Box 315)
    - International Student Travel Conference, 5th, 1953 (Box 11)
    - International Student Travel Conference, 6th, 1955-1956
    - International Student Travel Conference, 7th, 1956-1957
    - International Student Travel Conference, 8th, 1957-1958
    - International Student Travel Conference, 10th, 1959
    - International Student Travel Conference, 11th, 1960
    - International Student Travel Conference, 12th, 1961
    - International Student Travel Conference, 13th, 1962
    - International Student Travel Conference, 14th, 1964
    - International Student Travel Conference, 15th, 1965
    - Southeast Asian Student Seminar, Colombo, Ceylon, 1956 September 1-8 (Box 314)
  - Correspondence (Box 12)
    - General, 1951-1965
    - General, 1951-1965 (Box 13)
    - Avila, Raul, 1962-1963 (Box 14)
    - Baad, David, 1956-1963
    - Barros, Juan, 1955-1956
    - Dentzer, William T., 1952-1953
    - Eckstein, Peter, 1961-1963
    - Emmerson, Donald, 1962-1964
    - Gerin, Jacques, 1962-1963
    - Gunther, Magnus, 1960-1962
    - Ingram, Avrea, 1954-1956
    - Information Bulletin and The Student, 1955-1963
    - ISC Student Study Abroad, 1957
    - International Student Identity Card, 1958-1963 (Box 15)
    - International Student Press Card, 1957-1960
    - International Student Work Camp, 1958-1959
    - International University Exchange Fund, 1959-1963
    - International University Exchange Fund, 1959-1963 (Box 16)
    - Kiley, Robert, 1960-1962
    - Latin American Team, 2nd, 1957
    - Latin American Student Congress, 3rd, 1959-1960
    - Morgen, Gwyn, 1962-1964
    - Mutal, Sylvio, 1961-1962
    - Pan-African Student Conference, 1954-1958
    - Permanent Investment Commission
    - Research Commission
    - Singh, Jyoti S., 1963-1964
    - Supervision Commission, 1951-1959
    - Supervision Committee, 1962-1964 (Box 17)
    - Thompson, John, 1954-1956
    - World Food Congress
  - European Student Welfare, 1957, 1959
    - General File, 1957-1959
    - Delegated duties, 1954-1957
    - Finances, 1955-1956
    - Finances, 1957-1965 (Box 18)
      - Dues, 1954-1959
      - Funds, 1962-1963
    - Hungary, 1956-1957
    - Korn, Alexander, "History of the International Student Conference, ", 1950-1960
    - Ohio State Choral Dance Group
    - Project Questionnaires
    - Projects, 1962-1963
    - Prospect I, 1958
    - Publications
      - General
      - Circulars and Memoranda, 1955-1962
      - Circulars and Memoranda, 1955-1962 (Box 19)
      - National Union of Students Information Bulletins, v. l-8, 1952-1963 (Box 20)
      - National Union of Students Information Bulletins, v. 9-10, 1962-1964 (Box 21)
      - "The Student," v. l-5, 1956-1961 (Box 22)
      - "The Student," v. 6-9, 1962-1965 (Box 23)
      - Research and Information Commission, 1958-1962
      - Travel brochures
      - World Student Press Survey, circa 1958
      - Miscellany (Box 24)
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE, 1947-1966
  Correspondence of the NSA International Commission arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Allaway, William, 1949-1950 (Box 24)
  - Andrade, Fernando, 1961
  - Aragon, Manuel, 1957-1961
  - Aragon, Robert S., 1959-1963
  - Aswad, Richard N., 1957
  - Avila, 1963-1964
  - Baad, David, 1957-1960
  - Backoff, Robert, 1962-1965 (Box 25)
  - Baker, Patricia, 1949
  - Bakken, Harald, 1959-1963
  - Banet, Tony, 1957-1958
  - Babchick, Leonard, 1954-1960
  - Beck, Richard P., 1960
  - Becker, Paul, 1964
  - Berger, Fred, 1962, 1964-1966
  - Beyers, Robert W., 1954
  - Boitel, Hank, 1961
  - Briggs, Robert, 1956
  - Brock, Elmer P., 1951-1952
  - Buckner, Al, 1960
  - Carriere, Jean, 1963
  - Casey, Flo, 1960
  - Cava, Ralph Della, 1954-1959
  - Chary, Marge, 1960 (Box 26)
  - Cheen Sylvia, 1958-1960
  - Childers, Erskine, 1947-1950
  - Clemens, Walter, 1958-1960
  - Cooper, 1955 January
  - Crump, Frank, 1960-1961
  - Curry, Connie, 1956
  - Dale, Harvey P., 1957-1958
  - Dall, Hans, 1958
  - Dentzer, William, 1952-1956
  - Derecskey, Charles, 1956-1958
  - Dickson, Glenn, 1956-1957
  - Douglas, William, 1960-1961
  - Drasnin, Irving, 1957
  - Duberman, David, 1953-1954
  - Dkhdalevych, Olha, 1958-1959
  - Eccles, Peter, 1958-1960
  - Eckstein, Peter, 1957-1964
  - Edwards, James, 1954-1960
  - Einandi, Luigi, 1955-1961
  - Eisenach, Eldon, 1960
  - Eisenberg, Avria, 1952
  - Ellis, William, 1947-1955
  - Emmerson, Donald, 1963-1965
  - Farber, Barry, 1955-1956
  - Farrar, Curt, 1950 (Box 27)
  - Fischelis, Robert, 1950
  - Fisher, Frank, 1950-1956
  - Fisher, Joel, 1959-1950
  - Flad, Harvey, 1960-1961
  - Fogarty, Mary M., 1959
  - Foranini, Dennis, 1964-1965
  - Francis, Robert, 1963-1966
  - Freed, Merrill, 1953-1954
  - Gable, Edward, 1954
  - Garvey, Edward, 1962-1963
  - Gerin, Jacques, 1963-1964
  - Glass, Stan, 1959-1961
  - Glenn, Gary, 1959-1960
  - Glickman, Julius, 1964-1965
  - Golanski, Carl, 1960-1961 (Box 28)
  - Grant, James, 1950-1951
  - Gray, Clive, 1955-1960
  - Green, Reginald H., 1956-1957, 1961
  - Groves, Eugene, 1966
  - Gunther, Magnus, 1963
  - Hannon, Paul, 1960-1961
  - Harris, Ted, 1950-1956
  - Hatch, Diane, 1961
  - Hazelrigg, George, 1960-1961, 1963-1964
  - Hoffman, Donald, 1959-1960
  - Hornsby, Peter, 1958-1959
  - Houghton, Albert F., 1958
  - Idzik, Daniel, 1959-1961
  - Ingram, Avrea, 1951-1953
  - International Activities Commission, 1947-1959 (Box 29)
  - Iverson, Matthew J., 1960-1962 (Box 30)
  - Janusz, Larry, 1959-1960
  - Kaplan, Herbert, 1958-1959
  - Kelly, Robert, 1950-1951
  - Kennedy, Duncan, 1966
  - Khaw, Kenneth, 1963
  - Kiley, Robert, 1960-1963
  - Knight, Peter, 1961-1963
  - Korns, Alexander, 1963-1964
  - Kraus, Arthur J., circa 1960
  - Lamoureux-David Spencer, Thomas, 1963
  - Larkin (Box 31)
  - Lee, William, 1959-1961
  - Littig, David M., 1964-1965
  - Love, Joseph, 1962
  - Lopez, Nina, 1965 (Box 314)
  - Lunn, Harry, 1954-1957 (Box 31)
  - McClaskey, William C., 1963-1965
  - Marcus, Isabel S., 1959-1961
  - Miller, Richard M., 1958-1960
  - Moongo, David, 1967
  - Moore, Clement, 1957-1960 (Box 32)
  - Moore, Forrest, 1963-1964
  - Murrow, Edward R., 1952
  - Olsen, Thomas, 1962-1966
  - Potter, Kenneth P., 1959
  - Ramsey, Meta, 1964
  - Rettig, Richard, 1961
  - Rogers, Helen, J., 1950-1960
  - Rosa, Osvaldo, 1963-1965
  - Rosenbaum, Peter, 1960
  - Schwartz, Gene, 1949-1951
  - Scott, James, 1958-1963
  - Shingler, John, 1962-1963
  - Sigmund, Paul E., Jr., 1955-1956
  - Smith, Donald, 1962-1964
  - Smith, James, 1947-1949
  - Smith, Robert, 1948 (Box 33)
  - Smith, Tony, 1962-1963
  - Spencer, David, 1963-1965
  - Stearns, Richard, 1967
  - Stolberg, Irving, 1962
  - Theroux, Eugene, 1962
  - Thomas, Frederic C., Jr., 1953
  - Tinker, Gerald, 1963
  - Turner, Thomas, 1960-1961, 1964
  - Valencia, Alberto, 1960-1961
  - Welsh, William, 1948
  - West, Robert, 1947-1951
  - Witherspoon, Robert E., 1964-1966
  - Young, Crawford, 1956-1961
  - Miscellany, 1947-1949
  - Miscellany, 1950-1960 (Box 34)
  - Miscellany, 1961-1965 (Box 35)
- INTERNATIONAL UNION OF STUDENTS FILE, 1946-1966
  Correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, reports, and financial records collected by the NSA International Commission and relating to the activities of the International Union of Students within communist controlled countries, arranged alphabetically by title or subject.
  - Background and historical data (Box 36)
  - Background and historical data. Includes history of relations with the U.S.N.S.A. (Box 315)
  - Conferences, circa 1948-1964 (Box 36)
  - Constitution, 1946-1947
  - Correspondence, 1946-1961 (Boxes 37, 324)
  - Finances, 1946-1948, 1954-1956 (Box 38)
  - International Student Meeting, Yugoslavia, 1956 July
  - Meetings, Executive
    - Praha, 1947 February 5-13, 1948 January
    - Paris, 1948 September
    - Bologna, 1949 June 27-July 2
    - London, 1950 February (Box 39)
    - Berlin, 1951 January 13-18
    - Peking, 1951 April
    - Hungary, 1952 March
    - Vienna, 1954 January 19-21
    - Prague, 1955 March
    - Sofia, 1955 August 26-31
    - Bucharest, 1956 January 24-27
    - Tunis, 1960 February
    - Prague, 1961 November 1-7
    - Algiers, 1963 April
    - Budapest, 1964 February
    - Czechoslovakia, 1965 December 6-14
  - Meetings, Council
    - Praha, 1946 August
    - Prague, 1947 July-August
    - Paris, 1948 September (Box 40)
    - Sofia, 1949 September
    - Bucharest, 1952 September (Box 41)
    - Moscow, 1954 August
    - Sofia, 1955 August
    - Havana, 1961 May-June
  - Meetings, World Student Congresses
    - lst, Prague, 1946 August
    - 2nd, Prague, 1950 August
    - 3rd, Prague, 1953 April (Box 42)
    - 4th, Prague, 1956 August-September
    - 5th, Peking, 1956 August-September
    - 6th, Bagdad, 1960 October
    - 7th, Leningrad, 1962 August
    - 7th, Leningrad, 1962 August (Box 315)
    - 8th, Sofia, 1964 November-December
    - 8th, Sofia, 1964 November-December (Box 42)
  - Meetings, Unity, 1952 (Box 43)
  - Memoranda, 1958-1963
  - Miscellany
  - Organization, 1956-1957, 1960
  - Policy, 1947-1957 (Box 44)
  - Publications, 1946-1965
    - General, 1946-1963
    - General, 1946-1963 (Box 45)
    - Circulars, 1946-1963
    - Circulars, 1951-1963 (Box 46)
    - News Service, 1947-1966
    - Press and Information, 1946-1957
    - IUS News Service, 1950-1951
    - IUS News Service, 1955-1962 (Box 47)
    - IUS News Service, 1956-1959 (Box 48)
    - IUS News Service, World Student News, v. l-5, 1947-1952 (Box 49)
    - IUS World Student News, v. 6-12, 1953-1958 (Box 50)
    - IUS World Student News, v. 13-19, 1959-1965 (Box 51)
    - Miscellany
  - Reports (Box 52)
    - General
    - Great Britain, 1952-1953
    - Canada, 1946-1952
    - Czechoslovakia, 1947-1948
    - Denmark, 1947-1952
    - Dominican Republic, 1964-1965
    - France, 1948-1952 (Box 53)
    - Soviet Union, circa 1952
    - Switzerland, 1949-1950
    - Miscellaneous reports, 1959-1963
    - Miscellaneous reports, 1959-1963 (Box 54)
  - Seminars, 1954-1963
  - Structure and foundation
  - World Youth Festivals
    - lst, Prague, 1947 July-August
    - 2nd, Budapest, 1949 August
    - 3rd, Warsaw, 1953 August-September (Box 55)
    - 4th, Bucharest, 1953 August 2-16
    - 5th, Warsaw, 1955 July 31-August 14
    - 7th, Vienna, 1959 July-August
    - 8th, Helsinki, 1962 July-August (Box 56)
    - 9th, Vienna, 1966 January
- NATIONAL STUDENT ASSOCIATION FILE, 1947-1966
  Correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings, notes, and lists, relating to the activities of the NSA, the parent body of the International Commission, arranged alphabetically by title or subject.
  - Almanacs (Box 315)
    - General
    - 1962 (Box 56)
    - 1964
  - By-laws, 1952
  - Codification of policies, 1948 (Box 315)
  - Codification--policy declarations, resolutions and mandates, 1957-1958 (Box 56)
  - Codification--policy declaration, resolutions and mandates, 1958-1959
  - Codification and summary report, 1960-1961
  - Codification (in French), 1959-1960
  - Codification (in Spanish), 1959-1960
  - Constitution, 1947-1957 (Box 57)
  - Constitution, 1957-1958
  - Constitutional Convention, Madison, Wisconsin, Panel reports, 1947 August 3-September 7
  - Correspondence, 1953-1963
  - Correspondence, 1953-1963 (Box 58)
  - Executive Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 315)
  - File catagories, 1947-1960 (Box 58)
  - File catagories, 1956-1961, 1965
  - Financial reports, 1951-1965 (Box 314)
  - Handbook, 1966 (Box 58)
  - History (2 folders)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 59)
  - Student Congresses, l-18, 1948-1965
    - lst, Madison, Wisconsin, August 1948
    - 2nd, 1949
    - 3rd, 1950
    - 4th, University of Minnesota, 1951 August
    - 5th, University of Indiana, 1952 August 18-27
    - 6th, Columbus, Ohio, 1953 August 24-September 2
    - 7th, Ames, Iowa, 1954 August 22-31
    - 8th, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1955 August 21-31
    - 9th, Chicago, Illinois, 1956 August 21-31
    - 10th, University of Michigan, 1957 August 20-27
    - 11th, 1958 (Box 60)
    - 12th, University of Illinois, 1959 August 24-September 3
    - 13th, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1960 August 22-September 1
    - 14th, Madison, Wisconsin, 1961 August 20-30 (Box 61)
    - 15th, Ohio State University, 1962 August 19-30
    - 16th, Indiana University, 1963 August 18-29 (Box 62)
    - 16th, Indiana University, 1963 August 18-29 (Box 315)
    - 17th, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1964 August 16-27
    - 17th, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1964 August 16-27 (Box 62)
    - 18th, Madison, Wisconsin, 1965 August 22-September 2
    - 19th, Champaign, Illinois, 1966 August 20-September l
    - 20th, 1967
  - Publications, 1948-1960 (Box 63)
    - International Bulletin
    - National Student News
    - Student Government Bulletin and Report
    - Miscellaneous (Boxes 63-65)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 319)
  - Publicity (Box 65)
  - Regional Reports, 1947-1966 (Box 66)
  - Reports from NSA field staff (national and international), 1945-1951
  - Reports from NSA field staff, 1951-1953 (Box 67)
  - Reports from NSA field staff, 1954-1961 (Box 68)
  - Reports from NSA field staff, 1962-1967 (Boxes 69-71)
- OFFICE FILE, 1947-1965
  Correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings, memoranda, notes, lists, and printed matter of the NSA International Commission, arranged alphabetically by title or subject.
  - Correspondence (Box 72)
    - General
    - International Correspondence Exchange Subcommission (Box 73)
    - International and National Executive Boards and Committees (Box 74)
    - International Activities Control Board, 1952-1954
    - International Advisory Board, 1948-1963
    - National Advisory Board, 1959-1961 (Box 75)
    - National Advisory Council, 1947-1956
    - National Executive Committee, 1947-1962 (Box 76)
    - National Interim Committee, 1962
    - National Supervisory Board
      - 1963 August - 1964 August
      - 1965 November
      - 1965 November (Box 315)
      - 1966 April 29-May 1
      - 1966 April 29-May 1 (Box 76)
    - Youth Service Abroad Conference, 1961 February 3-4
  - Campus Administrator (Box 77)
  - Financial Reports, 1951-1965
    - Expense Voucher
    - General
  - International Affairs-Vice President, 1954, 1958-1960, 1963-1964
  - Memoranda, 1953-1967 (Box 78)
  - News releases, 1957-1961 (Box 79)
  - Personnel
  - Policy directives, 1950-1957
  - Policy and Programs Handbook
  - Prospectives, 1961-1965
  - Publications (Boxes 80-84)
    - Domestic and foreign mailings, 1947-1965
    - Membership lists, 1960-1963 (Box 85)
  - Publicity (Box 86)
  - Scholarship applicants, A-L
  - Scholarship applicants, M-Z (Box 87)
  - Scholarships, general information
  - Scholarships Abroad for Americans
  - Eisenhower Scholarships
  - Stencils on all National Student Association work, 1948-1949
  - Staff, general information, 1948-1961
  - Staff meetings, 1947-1953
- PROJECTS FILE, 1946-1963
  Correspondence, reports, and printed matter relating to special projects undertaken by the NSA International Commission, arranged alphabetically by title or project.
  - African - Middle East Team, 1956-1957 (Box 88)
  - African scholarships in U.S., 1953
  - African Student Conference, Howard University, 1953 June ll-13
  - African Students leaving Eastern Europe for U.S., 1960-1961
  - African team, 1954-1958
  - African team, applications, 1954-1957
  - Afro-Asian Student Congress, 1957-1958
  - Alabama case, University of Alabama segregation case, 1955-1956
  - Algerian Assistance, (International Algerian Student Emergency Fund), 1958-1959
  - Algerian refugee coupons, 1960-1961
  - Algerian scholarships, 1958-1960
  - Amigos project, 1964
  - American Bookshelf, 1955-1956 (Box 89)
  - Arab lectures, 1953-1954
  - Arab refugees, 1953
  - Argentine visit to U.S., 1951, 1956
  - Art tour U.S., 1948
  - Asian activities, 1954
  - Asian Choir Tour, 1955
  - Asian drama team, 1955
  - Asian subcommission, 1956-1957
  - Asian team, 1955-1956
  - Athletics, 1951-1955
  - Atomic energy, 1955-1961
  - Atomic energy, 1959-1961 (Box 90)
  - Atomic X-Ray machine, 1955
  - Austrian student and teacher Goodwill tours to North America, 1949-1951
  - Book exchange, 1958-1961
  - Brotherhood Week, 1954-1956
  - Brazilian delegation, 1960
  - Brazilian Student exchange, 1958
  - Brazilian Student tour, 1952
  - Bowdoin Plan (Bowdoin College international understanding), 1948
  - Campus administrator, 1953-1954
  - Campus international programming information, 1951-1964
  - Campus international responsibility, 1960
  - Canadian affairs, 1946-1952 (Box 91)
  - Canadian bi-culturalism, 1964
  - Canadian exchange, 1955-1958
  - Carleton plan for foreign and displaced students
  - Children's camp in France, 1947-1948
  - Chilian exchange, 1957, 1961
  - China, 1960
  - Chinese student investigation, 1954-1955
  - Chinese student relief, 1949
  - Colonialism (French Overseas Territories), 1956
  - Colorado University placement of displaced persons, 1949-1950
  - Columbia University Student Council, 1961
  - Compilation of study opportunities in American Universities
  - Conference on Foreign Student Affairs, 1955-1956
  - Conference on Foreign Student Affairs, 1957-1959 (Box 92)
  - Conference on International Education, 1950-1951
  - Congolese tour, 1960
  - Congressional Contracts, 1958-1961
  - Court decision on segregation, 1954
  - Cuban delegation, 1960